Sosuke Nishikawa

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

📞 090-4161-7403 | 🖂 sosuken115@gmail.com | 🏕 sosuke115.github.io | 🗘 Sosuke115 | in sosuke-nishikawa-2100581a0 | 💆 @ponyo_ponyo115

Personal Profile Statement

A master's student at the University of Tokyo with experience in software and machine learning. Skilled at operating in a wide range of platforms and programming. Praised for the ability to work hard and to achieve goals. Currently studying natural language processing using deep learning.

Education

- Master's student in Information Science and Technology, The University of Tokyo, Echizen lab. Apr. 2020 Mar.
 2022 (Expected graduation)
- B.E. in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, The University of Tokyo, Tsuruoka lab. Mar. 2020, GPA: 3.8/4.2

Work and Research Experience _____

Echizen Lab, Nationa	l Institute of	Informatics
----------------------	----------------	-------------

Tokyo, Japan Apr. 2020 - PRESENT

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Studio Ousia

· Research adversarial examples in NLP

Tokyo, Japan

RESEARCH ENGINEER (PART TIME)

Feb. 2020 - PRESENT

• Research multilingual models

CyberAgent Inc.

Tokyo, Japan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Feb. 2021 - Feb. 2021

• Worked on information extraction on web documents

SONY

RESEARCH ENGINEER INTERN

Tokyo, Japan Sep. 2020 - Oct. 2020

• Research on dialogue systems

Cookpad Inc.

Tokyo, Japan

RESEARCH ENGINEER INTERN

Sep. 2020 - Sep. 2020

Developed the API that predicts ingredients from recipes

Tokyo, Japan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Wantedly Inc.

Stockmark Inc.

Aug. 2020 - Aug. 2020

• Developed the model that recommends connections using graph embeddings

Tokyo, Japan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (PART TIME)

Dec. 2018 - Dec. 2019

· Created web application that allows users to understand at a glance who is familiar with which fields

Publication

Bag-of-Entities for Improving Multilingual Models using Language Link on Knowledge

Base (エンティティの言語間リンクに基づく多言語モデルの構築)

- Proceedings of the 27th Annual Meeting of the Association for Natural Language Processing (NLP2021)
- Sosuke Nishikawa, Ikuya Yamada, Yoshimasa Tsuruoka, Isao Echizen

A Model for Recommending Cooking Ingredients Using Multi-Label Classification ($abla \mathcal{P}$

ラベル分類による材料推薦モデル)

- Proceedings of the 27th Annual Meeting of the Association for Natural Language Processing (NLP2021)
- Yusuke Fukasawa, Jun Harashima, Sosuke Nishikawa

Analysis of bilingual word embeddings using pseudo corpus generated from Unsupervised Machine Translation (教師なし機械翻訳の出力結果から作成した Bilingual Word Embeddings の分析)

- Proceedings of the 26th Annual Meeting of the Association for Natural Language Processing (NLP2020)
- Sosuke Nishikawa, Yoshimasa Tsuruoka

Data Augmentation for Learning Bilingual Word Embeddings with Unsupervised Machine Translation

- arXiv preprint
- Sosuke Nishikawa, Ryokan Ri and Yoshimasa Tsuruoka

Studio Ousia at the NTCIR-15 SHINRA2020-ML Task

- 15th NTCIR Conference
- · Sosuke Nishikawa, Ikuya Yamada

Award

JGC-S scholarship foundation

Scholarship for study abroad program.

Competences .

Languages Japanese (*native*), English (*conversant*, IELTS 6.0)

Programming Python, JavaScript/TypeScript, d3.js, Ruby, C/C++, ŁTEX, HTML/CSS, MySQL, Google Apps Script, Java, Go

Libraries and Services Pytorch, Chainer, Tensorflow, Keras, Docker, Amazon Web Service, Google Cloud Platform

Competitive prog. Atcoder sosuke115 (rate 1003)